[
    { "question" : "Быть", "answer" : "to be", "pronunciation" : "/bɨtʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Иметь", "answer" : "to have", "pronunciation" : "/ɪˈmʲetʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Хотеть", "answer" : "to want", "pronunciation" : "/xɐˈtʲetʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Говорить", "answer" : "to speak", "pronunciation" : "/ɡɐvɐˈrʲitʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Думать", "answer" : "to think", "pronunciation" : "/ˈdumətʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Любить", "answer" : "to love", "pronunciation" : "/lʲʉˈbʲitʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Знать", "answer" : "to know", "pronunciation" : "/znatʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Смотреть", "answer" : "to watch", "pronunciation" : "/smɐrˈtʲetʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Работать", "answer" : "to work", "pronunciation" : "/rɐˈbotətʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Слушать", "answer" : "to listen", "pronunciation" : "/sluˈʂatʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Учиться", "answer" : "to study", "pronunciation" : "/utɕɪtʲˈsʲa/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Гулять", "answer" : "to walk", "pronunciation" : "/ɡʊˈlʲatʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Понимать", "answer" : "to understand", "pronunciation" : "/pənʲɪˈmatʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Сидеть", "answer" : "to sit", "pronunciation" : "/sʲɪˈdʲetʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Жить", "answer" : "to live", "pronunciation" : "/ʐɨtʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Видеть", "answer" : "to see", "pronunciation" : "/ˈvʲidʲɪtʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Спрашивать", "answer" : "to ask", "pronunciation" : "/sprɐˈʂivətʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Рисовать", "answer" : "to draw", "pronunciation" : "/rʲɪsɐˈvatʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Читать", "answer" : "to read", "pronunciation" : "/tɕɪˈtatʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Путешествовать", "answer" : "to travel", "pronunciation" : "/putʲɪʂɪˈstvovətʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Покупать", "answer" : "to buy", "pronunciation" : "/pəkʊˈpatʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Продавать", "answer" : "to sell", "pronunciation" : "/prədɐˈvatʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Готовить", "answer" : "to cook", "pronunciation" : "/ɡətɐˈvʲitʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Нравиться", "answer" : "to like", "pronunciation" : "/nˈravʲɪtʲsə/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Помогать", "answer" : "to help", "pronunciation" : "/pəmɐˈɡatʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Спать", "answer" : "to sleep", "pronunciation" : "/spatʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Ездить", "answer" : "to go (by transport)", "pronunciation" : "/jɪzˈdʲitʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "Ходить", "answer" : "to walk", "pronunciation" : "/xɐˈdʲitʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "to walk" },
    { "question" : "Развлекаться", "answer" : "to have fun", "pronunciation" : "/rəzvliˈkatʲsʲə/", "part_of_speech" : "to walk" },
    { "question" : "Искать", "answer" : "to look for", "pronunciation" : "/ˈiskatʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "to walk" },
    { "question" : "Уезжать", "answer" : "to leave", "pronunciation" : "/ʊɪzˈʐatʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "to walk" },
    { "question" : "Дом", "answer" : "house", "pronunciation" : "/dom/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Работа", "answer" : "work", "pronunciation" : "/rɐˈbotə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Школа", "answer" : "school", "pronunciation" : "/ˈʂkolə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Улица", "answer" : "street", "pronunciation" : "/ʊˈlʲitsə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Машина", "answer" : "car", "pronunciation" : "/mɐˈʂinə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Квартира", "answer" : "apartment", "pronunciation" : "/kvɐrˈtʲirə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Время", "answer" : "time", "pronunciation" : "/ˈvrʲemʲə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Семья", "answer" : "family", "pronunciation" : "/sʲɪˈmʲja/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Деньги", "answer" : "money", "pronunciation" : "/dʲɪˈnʲɡʲi/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Ребенок", "answer" : "child", "pronunciation" : "/rʲɪbɪˈnok/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Книга", "answer" : "book", "pronunciation" : "/ˈknʲiɡə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Магазин", "answer" : "store", "pronunciation" : "/mɐˈɡazʲɪn/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Ресторан", "answer" : "restaurant", "pronunciation" : "/rʲɪstɐˈran/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Компьютер", "answer" : "computer", "pronunciation" : "/kəmpʊjˈtʲer/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Телефон", "answer" : "telephone", "pronunciation" : "/tɪlʲɪˈfon/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Город", "answer" : "city", "pronunciation" : "/ɡɐˈrot/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Здание", "answer" : "building", "pronunciation" : "/ˈzdʲanʲɪje/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Музыка", "answer" : "music", "pronunciation" : "/mʊˈzɨkə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Река", "answer" : "river", "pronunciation" : "/ˈrʲɛkə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Одежда", "answer" : "clothes", "pronunciation" : "/ɐˈdʲeʐdə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Завтрак", "answer" : "breakfast", "pronunciation" : "/zɐfˈtrak/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Обед", "answer" : "lunch", "pronunciation" : "/ɐˈbʲet/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Ужин", "answer" : "dinner", "pronunciation" : "/ʊˈʐin/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Вода", "answer" : "water", "pronunciation" : "/ˈvodə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Еда", "answer" : "food", "pronunciation" : "/ˈjedə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Медицина", "answer" : "medicine", "pronunciation" : "/mʲɪdʲɪˈtsɨnə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Доктор", "answer" : "doctor", "pronunciation" : "/ˈdoktər/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Больница", "answer" : "hospital", "pronunciation" : "/bɐlʲˈnitsə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Поезд", "answer" : "train", "pronunciation" : "/pɐˈjest/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Самолет", "answer" : "airplane", "pronunciation" : "/səmɐˈlʲet/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Кофе", "answer" : "coffee", "pronunciation" : "/ˈkofʲɪ/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Чай", "answer" : "tea", "pronunciation" : "/tɕaj/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Вино", "answer" : "wine", "pronunciation" : "/ˈvʲinə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Пиво", "answer" : "beer", "pronunciation" : "/ˈpʲivə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Коллега", "answer" : "colleague", "pronunciation" : "/kɐˈlʲeɡə/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Друг", "answer" : "friend", "pronunciation" : "/druk/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Мать", "answer" : "mother", "pronunciation" : "/matʲ/", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "Хороший", "answer" : "good", "pronunciation" : "/xɐˈroʂɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Плохой", "answer" : "bad", "pronunciation" : "/ˈpɫoxɐj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Большой", "answer" : "big", "pronunciation" : "/ˈboɫʲʂɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Маленький", "answer" : "small", "pronunciation" : "/mɐˈlʲenʲkʲɪj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Новый", "answer" : "new", "pronunciation" : "/ˈnovɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Старый", "answer" : "old", "pronunciation" : "/ˈstarɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Теплый", "answer" : "warm", "pronunciation" : "/ˈtʲepɫɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Холодный", "answer" : "cold", "pronunciation" : "/xɐˈɫodnɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Счастливый", "answer" : "happy", "pronunciation" : "/ˈɕtɕastɫʲɪvɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Неудачный", "answer" : "unlucky", "pronunciation" : "/nʲɪʊˈdatʂnɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Легкий", "answer" : "light", "pronunciation" : "/ˈlʲɛɡkʲɪj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Тяжелый", "answer" : "heavy", "pronunciation" : "/ˈtʲaʐɨlɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Быстрый", "answer" : "fast", "pronunciation" : "/ˈbɨstrɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Медленный", "answer" : "slow", "pronunciation" : "/ˈmʲɛdɫʲɪnnɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Красивый", "answer" : "beautiful", "pronunciation" : "/kraˈsʲivɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Уродливый", "answer" : "ugly", "pronunciation" : "/ʊrɐdˈlʲivɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Длинный", "answer" : "long", "pronunciation" : "/ˈdlʲinnɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Короткий", "answer" : "short", "pronunciation" : "/kɐˈrotkʲɪj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Чистый", "answer" : "clean", "pronunciation" : "/ˈtɕɨstɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Грязный", "answer" : "dirty", "pronunciation" : "/ˈɡrɨznɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Сладкий", "answer" : "sweet", "pronunciation" : "/ˈsɫatkʲɪj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Кислый", "answer" : "sour", "pronunciation" : "/ˈkʲislɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Соленый", "answer" : "salty", "pronunciation" : "/sɐˈlʲenɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Пресный", "answer" : "tasteless", "pronunciation" : "/ˈprʲesnɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Свежий", "answer" : "fresh", "pronunciation" : "/ˈsvʲeʐɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Сухой", "answer" : "dry", "pronunciation" : "/ˈsuxoj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Мокрый", "answer" : "wet", "pronunciation" : "/ˈmokrɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Горький", "answer" : "bitter", "pronunciation" : "/ˈɡorʲkʲɪj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Смешной", "answer" : "funny", "pronunciation" : "/ˈsmʲeʂnɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Серьезный", "answer" : "serious", "pronunciation" : "/sʲɪˈrʲeznɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Трудный", "answer" : "hard", "pronunciation" : "/ˈtrudnɨj/", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "Дома", "answer" : "at home", "pronunciation" : "/ˈdomə/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "Вчера", "answer" : "yesterday", "pronunciation" : "/ˈvtɕɛrə/", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" }
]